The Promise That Was Kept
(ナルト)クッ！
(オビト)俺は
そちら側に行くことはない。
I will never go over
to your side!
今までの道に後悔もない。
I have no regrets with
my path up until now.
ちゃんと…
見えたって… 言ったろ。
I told you I saw everything.
だったら 今更→
So…
don't…
火影の自分なんか想像すんな！
keep imagining yourself as Hokage!
(オビト)リンが見守りたかったのは
今のお前じゃねえよ！
The person Rin wanted to watch over
isn't the current you…
うちはオビトだ！
It was Obito Uchiha.
((カカシ : またお前のせいで
遅刻だな オビト。
We're late again because
of you…Obito.
(ミナト)行くよ オビト。
Let's go, Obito.
(リン)ごめん 今行くよ。
Sorry! We'll be right there.
リン…。
Rin…
そう その心の穴は
自分で埋めればよいのだ。
That's right…
You ought to fill in that hole
in your heart yourself…
他人など何の力にもならん。
Others will be of no help.
さあ こっちへ。
So…come over here.
来て 私は無視したりしない。
I won't ignore you.
さあ。
Come…
オビト。
Obito…
Hold on, Rin!
ちょっと待って リン。
そう 今のお前じゃ
リンには見向きもされねえよ。
That's right… Rin won't even turn
to look at the current you.
リンが見守りたかったのは
うちはオビトだ。
The one Rin wanted to watch over
is Obito Uchiha.
もういいだろ 俺は…。
Enough already…
I am…
(うちはオビトだ))
Obito Uchiha!
Now just come over, you bastard!
いいから来い この野郎！
みんなの力を。
Everyone's power…
なめんなってばよ！
Don't you dare underestimate it!
抜けた！
They're out!
– All right!
– We did it!
(ガイ)うおぉ！
Yes!
《俺は… 負けたのか…》
Did I…lose?
(２人)ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
((オビト : 大きく開いた地獄の穴を
月の夢が埋めてくれる。
The gaping hole of hell
that has opened
will be filled by
the moon's dreams…
俺の心には 何もありゃしない。
今はもう 痛みさえ感じやしない。
There's nothing in my heart!
I don't even feel pain anymore.
後ろめたく思わなくていい カカシ。
Don't feel so guilty, Kakashi.
この風穴は この地獄の世界に
開けられたものだ。
This hole was opened
by this hellish world.
(カカシ)
こんなので… こんなもので→
Do you really think that
something like this
本気で心の穴が埋まるとでも
思ってるのか!?
can fill that hole in your heart?!
生きていた
リンの思いまで消すなよ！
Don't erase the memories
of the real Rin!
リンは命をかけて
里を守り 残そうとしたんだ。
Rin sacrificed herself to protect
and save the village!
ひとりで妄想ばかり
穴に詰め込んでみても→
You can try and fill that hole
with delusions all by yourself…
心の穴が埋まるわけがない！
But that hole will never be filled!
(カカシ)心の穴は 他のみんなが
埋めてくれるもんなんだよ))
The hole in one's heart gets filled
by others around you.
((行こう！
Let's go.
(ウフフッ))
う…。
リン…。
Rin…
(２人)ハァ ハァ ハァ…。
約束を守ったな うずまきナルト。
You kept your promise,
Naruto Uzumaki!
((だから 俺は
お前も助けてぇ！))
That's why I want
to save you too…
俺たちを
本当に助けやがるとはな。
And you really rescued us!
オッス 孫！
Right, Son!
ヘヘッ。
ラッキーだった。
We were lucky.
やるやよ。
本当にな。
He did it.
For real.
そうね。
よかった。
You're right.
I'm so glad!
ん？ コイツはたしか…。
Isn't he…?
えっ？
H-Hey!
おい！ 待て サスケ！
Wait, Sasuke!
ヤツは… ヤツはどうなった？
Where is he?!
Where'd he go?!
あっちだ まだ生きてる。
Over there! He's still alive!
《そうか 負けか…》
Right…I've lost…
(サスケ)カカシ…。
Kakashi!
Sasuke, we'll talk later.
サスケ 積もる話は あとだ。
急に出てきてすまないが→
I apologize for appearing
so suddenly…
かつて 同期で友であった俺に
コイツのけじめをつけさせてくれ。
But I was once
his classmate and friend…
So please let me
take responsibility for him.
カカシ先生 ソイツは 今…。
Kakashi Sensei!
He's now—!
父ちゃん。
Dad!
ヤツは 弱っている。
He's weak now!
今こそヤツに とどめを刺すときだ！
Now's the time to finish him!
いくぞ！
(みんな)お～っ！
Let's go!
– Right!
(綱手)待て！
Hold it!
オビト…。
Obito…
チャクラを引っ張りあったとき
キミの心の中を見せてもらったよ。
When we had that
chakra tug-of-war just now,
I got to see inside your heart.
ずいぶん息子が
ガミガミ説教したみたいだけど→
It seems like my son nagged
and lectured you quite a bit.
どうやら そういうところは
母親譲りみたいだね。
I think he might have gotten that
from his mother.
父ちゃん…。
Dad…
でも 本来
それをやるのは キミの役目だ。
But that duty actually falls…
on you.
オビトをホントに理解し
何かを言えるとしたら→
I think the one who truly
understands Obito
and should talk to him…
友達のキミだと思うよ カカシ。
is you, his friend…Kakashi.
そうだろ ナルト。
Isn't that right, Naruto?
Naruto, you two and
the Allied Forces should go
ナルト お前たちと連合は
初代様のサポートへ行ってくれ。
and help Lord First,
and seal Madara away.
マダラを封印するんだ。
あっ そうか！ アイツがまだだ！
Oh, right! We still need
to deal with him!
行くぞ サスケ！
Let's go, Sasuke!
I think you were younger
than Naruto is now.
今のナルトよりも
まだ小さかったかな。
覚えているかい？
４人でこなした任務の数々を…。
Do you remember?
All the missions that
the four of us went on?
As a Medic Ninja, Rin did
her utmost to protect you two.
リンは 医療忍者として
キミたち２人を必死に守ってた。
こんな状態を
望んじゃいなかったろうね。
She would never have wished
for a situation like this.
(ミナト)でも
そうさせてしまったのは→
But what caused this
is my responsibility.
俺の責任だ。
Can I start explaining
the mission to you?
((そろそろ任務の説明を
してもいいかな？
We're close to the border.
もう国境近くだしね。
(ミナト)いい？ このラインだよ。
All right, it's this line.
今 土の国が 草隠れの里を
侵略侵攻してきてるラインね。
It shows where the Land of Earth
is currently invading
the Hidden Grass Village.
もちろん敵は岩隠れの忍。
Hidden Stone Shinobi
are our enemies…
敵の前線には
すでに千の忍がいるって→
We have received intel
that 1000 ninja
already make up the front line.
情報なんだよね。
この前より更に前進してる。
They've advanced farther
than last time.
(カカシ)ま… 火の国も
草隠れと陸続きなのに→
The Land of Fire shares borders
with the Hidden Grass.
待ったをかけたのが遅すぎでしょ。
We should have stepped
in long ago.
これだけの進撃を
見せてるってことは→
Judging by the size of this advance…
they must have an efficient system
for reinforcement.
後方の支援が
スムーズに働いてるってことですね。
Hence, our mission is here…
at Kannabi Bridge.
そこで今回の任務…
ここ神無毘橋ね。
最前線では敵を叩くのに
たくさんの忍が必要になるよね。
To crush one's enemy
at the battlefront
requires an immense number
of ninja.
だから 俺たち妨害工作をする忍は
少数精鋭でやるしかないんだ。
So shinobi like us,
who focus on sabotage missions,
are forced to work in small,
select teams.
橋… ですか。
The bridge…you say?
ということは 潜入ミッションですね。
Then it's an infiltration mission?
うん。 カカシ隊 キミたちの任務は
敵の後方地域に潜入。
Team Kakashi…
Your mission is to infiltrate
the enemy's rear territory.
物資補給に使われている
この橋を破壊し→
You will destroy this bridge
which is used to transport supplies
and reinforcements.
敵の支援機能を分断。
And when this is done,
withdraw immediately.
その後 速やかに離脱すること。
(３人)はい！
– Yes, sir!
先生は？
And you, Sensei?
俺は前線で直接 敵を叩く。
I will face the enemy directly
on the battlefront.
キミたちの陽動にもなるからね。
I'll create a diversion for you.
とりあえず
今日はカカシ キミが隊長ね。
In any case,
Kakashi is your captain today.
国境までは
一緒に同行するけど→
We'll travel together to the border,
but after that
your mission commences!
そこからわかれて
ミッション スタートだよ。
(オビトたち)はい！
– Yes, sir!
(ミナト)ここからは二手にわかれる。
We'll be splitting up into
two teams from this point.
みんな頑張るんだよ。
Good luck to you all.
昨日の敵は たまたま単独で
偵察中だっただけで→
The enemy the other day was
doing surveillance alone.
これからは チーム戦になる。
気をつけて。
But here on out,
we'll be fighting teams.
Be careful…
(オビト)さっさと行こうぜ。
隊長さんよ))
Let's get going, Captain.
(ミナト)死んだはずの俺が
キミたちの前に→
It's no coincidence that I,
who should be dead,
am standing before
you two like this.
こうして立っているのは
偶然じゃない。
リンが そうさせたのかもね。
Perhaps it was Rin
who made it happen…
先生のくせに 何やってんだ って。
Her way of scolding me
for failing as your teacher.
(ミナト)リンを守れなくて
すまなかった。
I'm sorry I couldn't protect Rin.
(オビト)リンは… リンは→
Rin…
Rin was my only light and hope.
俺にとっての唯一の光明だった。
リンを失ってのち
俺の見る世界は変わってしまった。
After I lost Rin…
The world as I saw it, changed.
真っ暗な地獄だ。
It became a pitch black hell.
この世界に希望はない。
There's no hope in this world.
マダラになり代わって
世界を歩いたが→
I took Madara's identity
and walked the world.
更に それを確信するだけだった。
But all it did was confirm my belief.
この写輪眼をもってしても
結局は何も見えなかった。
Even with my Sharingan,
I couldn't see anything…
何もなかった。
There was nothing to see.
俺も はっきりとは わからない。
I don't know anything
for sure either…
なら 俺の新たな道は…。
Then…my new path is—!
確かに お前の歩こうとしたのも
一つの道だろう。
Without a doubt,
your path is just one of many.
本当は
間違いじゃないのかもしれない。
And it may not actually
be wrong either.
俺だって この世界が
地獄と思ったさ。
I've thought this world was hell too.
お前を失ったと思っていたし…。
I thought that you had died…
すぐあとに リンを失い→
And right after that, I lost Rin…
そして ミナト先生までも
失ったからね。
And I lost Minato Sensei as well.
でも…。
But…
((そういや 忘れてたぜ。
Oh yeah… I forgot…
俺だけ お前に→
I was the only one
who didn't give you a gift…
上忍祝いのプレゼント
やってなかったな カカシ。
for becoming a Jonin, Kakashi.
何がいいか 考えてたんだ。
I was wondering…
what to give you…
んでよ 今 思いついたんだ。
and I just had a thought.
なに 安心しろ。
Don't worry…
役に立たない
余計なもんじゃない。
It's not some useless,
extra baggage…
この俺の写輪眼をやるからよ。
I'm giving you…my Sharingan.
里のヤツらが なんて言おうと→
Whatever the village may say,
お前は 立派な上忍だ。
you are a great Jonin.
それが 俺の気持だ。
That's how I really feel…
(受け取ってくれ))
So please accept it.
はっきりとは わからないが→
Even though I don't know
anything for sure…
眼をこらして見ようとはしたんだ。
I tried my best to see
the world with this eye.
お前がくれた
写輪眼と言葉があれば→
I felt that as long as I had
your Sharingan and words…
見える気がしたんだよ。
I could see it.
(オビト)それが ナルトだってのか。
And what you saw is Naruto?
アイツの道が
なぜ失敗しないと言い切れる？
How can you be sure
his path won't fail?
いや…。
No…
アイツも失敗するかもしれないよ
そりゃね。
He may very well fail too.
Of course.
(オビト)俺とナルトは何が違う？
How is Naruto different from me?
なぜ ヤツに そこまで…。
Why do you go so far for him?
オビト… 今のお前よりは
失敗しないと断言できるからだ。
Because I can say
without hesitation
that he is less likely to fail
than the current you.
なぜだ！
Why is that?!
(カカシ)アイツが
道をつまずきそうなら→
Because if he trips and stumbles
on his path…
俺が助ける。
I'll help him.
なぜ… ヤツを助ける？
Why would you help him?
(カカシ)アイツは 自分の夢も現実も
諦めたりはしない。
He would never give up
on his dreams…or on reality.
そういうヤツだからさ。
That's the kind of guy he is.
見つけた！
Found him!
And the way he forges ahead
draws others towards him.
(カカシ)そして アイツの そういう
歩き方が仲間を引き寄せる。
つまずきそうなら助けたくなる。
He makes you want to reach out
when he's about to stumble.
そのサポートが多ければ多いほど
ゴールに近づける。
And the greater
the support behind you,
the closer you can get to your goal.
そこが違うのさ。
That's the difference.
大玉螺旋手裏剣!!
Massive Rasen Shuriken!
もっとだ。
もっと でけぇのいくぞ。
Bigger! We'll go with something
even bigger!
おう！
– Right!
この真っ暗な地獄に
本当に そんなものがあると…。
Do you really believe
such a thing is possible
in this pitch-black hell?
お前だって
見ようとすれば見えたはずだ。
I'm sure you could've seen it too,
if you had tried.
俺とお前は
同じ眼を持ってんだからな。
After all,
you and I have the same eyes.
(カカシ)信じる仲間が集まれば→
If comrades that you trust,
gather around you…
hope can take physical form
and become visible.
希望も形となって
見えてくるかもしれない。
俺は そう思うんだよ。
That's what I believe…
オビト。
Obito.
Naruto Uzumaki, huh?
Seems you've become friends
with that Fox Demon's brat, Gaara…
皆様 お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では 最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
(宮本)『木曜８時のコンサート
名曲！ にっぽんの歌』。
２時間スペシャル。
(松丸)今回は スペシャルならではの
豪華な企画が盛りだくさんです。